In this video, I will show you how to create a 3D model of Marvelous Designer.
The Reversal function can help your model to get the ideal line and grid number.
In Marvelous Designer, the model is a triangular face model.
You can change the grid type and convert it into a four-sided face model with one click.
Select the version you want to edit, then right-click the grid type.
Here we choose to optimize the four sides.
Your model will be automatically converted into a four-sided model that is close to precision.
Tips 1. The four-sided optimization function will move according to the shape of the panel and optimize the layout.
Prevent the triangular face first.
It is suitable for panels with a large body, sleeves, etc. and not so neat edges.
The four-sided grid function will place the panels according to the direction of the 2D interface.
Tips 2. Prioritize the panel to generate a completely horizontal vertical line.
At the edge of the slanted panel and the seam line, it will automatically connect and generate a triangular face.
It is suitable for a regular rectangular panel that can be converted into a belt.
Tips 3. Even if the panel is a regular rectangular panel, it must be placed in the 2D window to properly generate an horizontal vertical grid.
Tips 4. You can also change the width of the panel.
You can use the optimization function of Everywhere to optimize the grid number of the model.
Click Connect Everywhere.
Enter your target grid number here.
Then press the optimization button.
After the grid update is completed, you can observe that the number of grid numbers has decreased.
Tips 2.
In the current version, the component material cannot be four-sided in the current version, but you can also adjust the grid number.
Click the component column and select the component to be edited.
Pull to the bottom and re-fill the number of faces you want.
You can see that the grid density has decreased.
Or open the plane. The component model will be changed to exist in the form of a panel.
Tips 3. You can also use the slope tool to customize the slope line of the clothing.
Use the smart slope tool to create the slope model you need.
Tips 4. The corresponding slope model will automatically be created on the mirror panel.
Tips 5. You can connect multiple slope areas together.
Tips 6. You can also use the slope tool to customize the slope line of the clothing.
You can also use the slope tool to customize the slope model you need.
Finally, press the create button to create a slope.
Tips 7. Use the edit slope tool to adjust the points that do not match the edge.
Tips 8. The edge of the model will automatically generate black reference points according to the color relationship.
Tips 9. You can also use the create slope tool to directly create a four-sided slope.
Tips 10. In the create slope tool mode, press Ctrl and Shift and press a line.
You can also use the create slope tool to customize the slope model you need.
The points that do not fit the edge will also be added to the grid.
Tips 10. The new
points will be added to the black reference points.
In the 2D and 3D windows, you can configure and edit the
model and your own.
You can also change the size of the model.
For example, if you want to change the size of the model, you can change the size of the model
by changing the size of the model.
Or, you can change the size of the model by changing the size of the model.
This will determine whether you create a copy or replace the original grid by using the
retouching grid.
If you want to exit the network, please go to the file, exit, and select OBJ or FBX.
In the exit window, you can find the option of merging near the peak.
After opening the option, the peak within the range of the set merger will be merged.
You can open the display option to check the welding situation of the border peak.
The red high beam is the border peak of the merger.
The blue high beam is the border peak of the non-merging merger.
Click OK to exit.
Thank you for watching. See you next time.